A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Governor's Office, 1946, 1970-1985
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Governor's Office, 1946, 1970-1985
The Library of Virginia
43288, 43289, 43290, 43291 and 43292
0.35 cu. ft (1 box)
Virginia Governor's Office
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Tina M.G. Long, Virginia Division of Legislative Services, 910 Capitol Street, General Assembly Building - Room 261, Richmond, VA 23219, transferred and accessed 29 June 2007.
Biographical/Historical Information
During the colonial period of Virginia's history the governor, as an appointee of the Crown, was the colony's principal representative and upholder of royal authority. Although his powers were limited somewhat by the Council and by the laws passed by the House of Burgesses, the governor still had the authority to prorogue, adjourn, or dissolve the legislature, to confirm or veto its acts, to preside as the chief jurist of the colony, to command the provincial military forces, and to appoint many of the subordinate officers of government.
Most of these powers, excepting the military and appointive, were swept away by the American Revolution. The several revolutionary conventions assumed the executive role in 1774 and 1775 until the Committee of Safety was created in July 1775 to function in that capacity. The constitution adopted in 1776 made the governor subordinate to the legislative branch, elected by the General Assembly and circumscribed by a Council of State appointed by the assembly.
It was not until the constitution of 1851 was adopted that the power of the governor was strengthened appreciably. The Council of State was abolished, and the governor was popularly elected. In subsequent years his authority was consolidated and expanded to statute, and his veto power was restored. The state government reorganization act passed by the General Assembly on April 18, 1927, firmly established the governor as the chief administrative officer of a government composed of departments, the directors of which serve at the pleasure of the governor. In addition, the organization of the governor's staff has increased in size and complexity until it has become virtually a department itself: the Office of the Governor, encompassing both the chief executive and his staff.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Governor's Office, Records, are housed in one box (seven folders). The collection is arranged by Governor: I. Governor Charles S. Robb, 1982-1985; II. Governor John N. Dalton, 1978-1981; III. Governor Mills E. Godwin, Jr., 1974-1977; IV. Governor A. Linwood Holton, Jr., 1970-1973; and V. Governor William M. Tuck, 1948. These records are select copies of Executive Orders and proclamations and are arranged in reverse chronological order by year. Some of the subjects of Executive Orders include: declarations of a state of emergency, primarily in response to natural disasters (Hurricane Agnes), fuel and energy shortages (including lowering the speed limit to 55 miles per hour), and drought (1977). Proclamations are primarily for holidays including Martin Luther King, Jr., Law Day, Mother's Day, Yorktown Day, Veterans Day and Thanksgiving.These records were originally retained by the Virginia Division of Legislative Services.
Contents List
- Governor Charles S. Robb, 1982-1985 (accession 43288)., Extent: 1 folder. (Box 1)
  - EO 54 (1985) Federal Limit on Private Activity Bonds (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 54 (1985-Revised) Federal Limit on Private Activity Bonds (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 55 (1985) Continuing the Commonwealth Intergovernmental Review Process (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 56 (1985) Creating the Patrick Henry Memorial Commission (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 57 (1985) Declaration of a State of Emergency for the City of Clifton Forge, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 60 (1985) Declaration of a State of Emergency for Patrick County, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 61 (1985) Emergency Operations Plan, Volume III, Operational Survival Plan, War-Caused Disasters (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 64 (1985) Declaration of a State of Emergency for the Town of Big Stone Gap, Wise County, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 65 (1985) Declaration of a State of Emergency for Flash Flooding and Mudslides occurring throughout the Commonwealth of Virginia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 66 (1985) Use of Safety Belts by State Employees (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 47 (1984-Revised) Authority and Responsibility of the Governor's Secretaries (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 48 (1984-Revised) Delegation of Authority for Certain Actions Affecting Management of the Commonwealth (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 53 (1984) Emergency Operations Plan, Part I of Volume IV, Emergency Management of Resources in Peacetime (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 31 (1983) Job Training Partnership Act (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 32 (1983) Providing for Cooperation between the Virginia National Guard and the Virginia State Police in the Suppression of Drug Traffic and other Criminal Activities within the Commonwealth (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 33 (1983) Emergency Due to Winter Storm (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 34 (1983) Job Training Partnership Act (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 35 (1983) Assigning Responsibility to State Officials and State Agencies for Participation in the Federal Comprehensive Environmental Response and Liability Act of 1980 (Superfund Program) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 36 (1983) Confirmation of Responsibilities of Senior Executive Assistant (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 37 (1983) Creating the Governor's Commission to Increase Voter Registration in Virginia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 38 (1983) Inappropriate Conflicts Arising from Personal Business Interests (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 39 (1983) Creating the Governor's Business and Industry Advisory Committee on Crime Prevention (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 1 (1982) Equal Employment Opportunity (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 2 (1982) To Place a Moratorium on the Hiring of State Employees (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 3 (1982) Exempting Certain Staff Positions from the Personnel Act (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 4 (1982) Creating Governor's Economic Advisory Council (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 5 (1982) Creating Commission on Block Grants (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 6 (1982) Moratorium on Hiring by State Government (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 7 (1982) Emergency Operations Plan, Volume III, Operational Survival Plan, War-Caused Disaster (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 8 (1982) Creating 1982 Education Block Grants Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 9 (1982) Commonwealth of Virginia Emergency Operations Plan, Closing of the Chesapeake Bay Bridge-Tunnel (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 10 (1982) Creating Governor's Council on Physical Fitness and Sports (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 11 (1982) Creating Governor's Task Force to Combat Drunk Driving (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 12 (1982) Executive Manpower Control Program (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 13 (1982) Creating Governor's Task Force on Science and Technology (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 14 (1982) Declaration of a State of Emergency for Buchanan County, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 15 (1982) Promulgation of Volume II, Emergency Operations Plan for Peacetime Disasters (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 15 (1982-Revised) Promulgation of Volume II, Emergency Operations Plan for Peacetime Disasters (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 16 (1982) Creating Governor's Advisory Board of Economists (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 17 (1982) Legislative Coordination (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 18 (1982) Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Advisory Council (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 19 (1982) Creating the Governor's Advisory Committee on Small Business (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 21 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Administration and Finance (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 21 (1982-Revised) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Administration and Finance (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 22 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Commerce and Resources (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 22 (1982-Revised) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Commerce and Resources (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 23 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Education (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 24 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Human Resources (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 25 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Public Safety (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 26 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Transportation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 26 (1982-Revised) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Transportation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 27 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Assistant Secretary for Financial Policy/Director of the Department of Planning and Budget (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 28 (1982) Delegation of Authority for Certain Actions Affecting Management of the Commonwealth (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 29 (1982) Creating Governor's Commission on Virginia's Future (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EO 32 (1982) Authority and Responsibility of Certain Agencies and Individuals Governing Certain State-Owned Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Governor John N. Dalton, 1978-1981 (accession 43289)., Extent: 2 folders. (Box 1)
  - EO 47 (1981) Establishment of a State Advocacy Office for Virginia's Developmentally Disabled Citizens (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 48 (1981) Restoration of License of Otis Eugene Pinion to Practice Law (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 49 (1981) Regulations Governing Certain State-Owned Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 54 (1981) Allocation of State Ceiling under the Mortgage Subsidy Bond Tax Act of 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Soybean Referendum, signed 20 January 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Proclamation: Special Session of the General Assembly, signed 23 February 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Law Day, signed 13 March 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mother's Day, signed 8 April 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jack Jouett Day, signed 16 March 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Battle Off the Virginia Capes Day, signed 8 April 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 37 (1980) Delegation of Authority for Certain Actions (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 37 (1980-Amended) Delegation of Authority for Certain Actions Affecting Management of the Commonwealth (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 38 (1980) Governor's Employment and Training Council (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 39 (1980) State of Emergency Record Winter Storm, Tidewater and Eastern Shore (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 40 (1980) State of Emergency Due to Oil Spills (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 41 (1980) Prohibiting the Taking of Crabs and Fish from the Chesapeake Bay/James River and Its Tributaries (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 42 (1980) Promulgation of Volume II, Emergency Operations Plan for Peacetime Disasters (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 43 (1980) Rescinding EO 33 (1979) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 44 (1980) Prohibiting the Taking of Crabs and Fish from the Chesapeake Bay/James River and Its Tributaries (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 45 (1980) Declaring a Water Resource Emergency in Southeastern Virginia (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 46 (1980) Concerning a Water Resource Emergency in Southeastern Virginia (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Handicapped Parking at State Facilities (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Martin Luther King Day (1 January 1980), signed 10 December 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Law Day (1 May 1980), signed 3 April 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Administration and Finance Directive No. 1-80, issued 6 May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Administration and Finance Directive No. 2-80, issued 9 May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mother's Day (11 May 1980), signed 17 April 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Administration and Finance Directive No. 4-80, issued 3 July 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitution Week (17-23 September 1980), signed 19 August 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TV for Learning Week, signed 19 September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Emergency Conservation Month (October 1980), signed 4 September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1st Week October 1980), signed 25 September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Establishing the Virginia Corn Commission, issued 10 October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1980), signed 30 July 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Veterans Day (11 November 1980), signed 10 September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thanksgiving Day (27 November 1980), signed 6 November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 21 (1979) Emergency Operations Plan, Part I of Volume IV, Emergency Management of Resources in Peacetime (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 22 (1979) Gasoline Supplies Allocated in the Counties of Arlington, Fairfax, Loudoun, Prince William and Cities of Alexandria, Falls Church, Fairfax, Manassas and Manassas Park (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 23 (1979) Mandatory Gasoline Sales Restrictions for same mentioned in EO 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 24 (1979) Mandatory Gasoline Sales Restrictions of Staggered House of Weekday amends paragraph II(A) of EO 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 25 (1979) Conditional Pardon to John Edward Thomasson and Terminating Parole Supervision (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 26 (1979) Assignment of Agencies and Collegial Bodies to Secretaries (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 27 (1979) Rescinding Certain Executive Orders Issued between 1976 and 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 28 (1979) Providing Emergency Increases in Gross Weight and Maximum Length of Motor Vehicles on Virginia Highways (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 29 (1979) State of Emergency: Storms Buchanan County (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 30 (1979) State of Emergency: Storms Rappahannock County (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 31 (1979) State of Emergency: from Tropical Storm David (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 32 (1979) State of Emergency: Storms Southwest, Central and Southside (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 33 (1979) Mandatory Gasoline Sales (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 34 (1979) Governor's Employment and Training Council (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 35 (1979) CETA Balance of State Planning Council (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EO 36 (1979) Overall Advisory Council on Needs of Handicapped Children and Adults (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Statement by Governor John N. Dalton on Employee-Employer Relationships in Public Sector, 6 February 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Landscape Architecture Week (23-29 April 1979), signed 12 April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Law Day (1 May 1979), signed 19 April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mother's Day (13 May 1979), signed 12 April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitution Week (17-23 September 1979), signed 6 September 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TV for Learning Week (25 September 1979), signed 13 September 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1979), signed 20 September 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1979), signed 2 August 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Proposed New Forms for Disclosure of Lobbying Expenses, Retainers and Salaries submitted, 23 October 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Veterans Day (11 November 1979), signed 24 August 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Special Executive Order 1 (1978) Special Undercover Identification (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 1 (1978) Equal Employment Opportunity (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 2 (1978) Governor's Manpower Services Council (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 3 (1978) State of Emergency from heavy rains and severe flooding (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 4 (1978) Coal Strike (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 5 (1978) Division of Energy, State Office of Emergency Services (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 6 (1978) Rescinding EO 4 (1978) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 7 (1978) State of Emergency (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 8 (1978) Designation of the Department of Planning and Budget (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 9 (1978) Continue the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Advisory Council (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 10 (1978) Office of Governor to be Informed of Proposed Legislation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 11 (1978) Authority and Responsibility of the Secretary of Administration and Finance (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 12 (1978) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Commerce and Resources (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 13 (1978) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Education (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 14 (1978) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Human Resources (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 15 (1978) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Public Safety (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 16 (1978) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Transportation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 17 (1978) Rescinding Certain Executive Orders Issued Between 1902 and 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 18 (1978) Rescinding Certain Executive Orders Issued Between 1946 and 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 19 (1978) Emergency Operations Plan, Volume III, Operational Survival Plan, War-Caused Disaster (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EO 20 (1978) Virginia Energy Resources Advisory Commission (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arbor Day (March 1978), signed 3 March 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proclamations, Amendments to Virginia Constitution, 5 December 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proclamation, Mother Vehicle Inspection, issued 18 July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Energy Conservation Month (October 1978), signed 27 September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Law Day (1 May 1978), issued 19 April 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parks and Recreation Month (June 1978), issued 26 May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - TV for Learning Week (September 1978), issued 5 September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1978), issued 29 September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1978), issued 10 October 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Veterans Day (11 November 1978), issued 11 July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Thanksgiving Day (23 November 1979), issued 17 October 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Governor Mills E. Godwin, Jr., 1974-1977 (accession 43290)., Extent: 2 folders. (Box 1)
  - Emergency Executive Order 1 (1977) Limiting Consumption of Fuel Oil, Electricity, Kerosene, Natural or Bottled Gas (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Executive Order 2 (1977) to Amend and Readopt EEO 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Executive Order 3 (1977) to Amend and Readopt EEO 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 48 (1977) Local Government Advisory Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 49 (1977) State Human Services Information and Referral Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 50 (1977) Establishing Rank of Superintendent of State Police (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 51 (1977) Request for Emergency Transportation for People who cross the Garrison Memorial Bridge, which was Struck by the Tanker Marine Floridian (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 52 (1977) Develop/Establish the Virginia Forms Management Program (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 53 (1977) Designate Department of Purchases and Supply as the Official Agency to Acquire, Store and Distribute Federal Personal Property (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 54 (1977) State Plan for the Emergency Management of Resources (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 55 (1977) Establishment of State Office for Virginia Developmental Disabilities Protection and Advocacy System (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 56 (1977) State of Emergency (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 57 (1977) Employee and Organizational Training and Development (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 58 (1977) Travel Regulations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 59 (1977) Interim Plan for the Emergency Management of Energy Resources (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 60 (1977) Establishment of State Office for Virginia Developmental Disabilities Protection and Advocacy System (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Harvesting Fisheries and Subfreezing Temperatures and Ice, signed 19 January 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: City of Danville and Subfreezing Temperatures and Natural Gas and Other Heating Fuels Shortage, signed 28 January 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Municipal Water and Sewage Systems from Subfreezing Temperatures and Ice, signed 14 February 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Southwestern and Western Virginia from Heavy Rains and Record Flooding, signed 5 April 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jack Jouett Day (4 June 1977), signed 6 April 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Natural Bridge of Virginia Bicentennial Day (5 July 1977) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Severe Drought and High Temperatures, Damage to Crops and Cattle, signed 7 July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Town of Louisa, signed 20 July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Town of Monterey, Highland County, signed 28 July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Town of Vienna, signed 2 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Town of Stuart, signed 18 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage City of Buena Vista, signed 12 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage City of Norfolk, signed 18 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage City of Virginia Beach, signed 18 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Town of Leesburg, signed 18 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage City of Chesapeake, signed 18 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitutional Week (17 September 1977), signed 22 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage County of Prince William, signed 22 August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Town of Mineral, signed 2 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage County of Louisa, signed 6 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitutional Week (17 September 1977), signed 6 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage County of Loudoun, signed 12 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage Throughout the Commonwealth, signed 14 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage County of Fairfax, signed 14 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage City of Alexandria, signed 14 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Veterans Day (11 November 1977), signed 26 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1977), signed 27 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1977), signed 28 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Thanksgiving Day (24 November 1977), signed 4 October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage City of Charlottesville, signed 7 October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Local Emergency: Prolonged Drought/Water Shortage County of Albemarle, signed 7 October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Substantial Flooding Smyth County and Southwest Virginia, signed 8 November 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 28 (1976) Promulgate and Issue Volume II of the Emergency Operations Plan for Peacetime Disasters (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 29 (1976) Establish the Virginia Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Advisory Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 30 (1976) Promulgate and Issue the Virginia Emergency Operations Plan, Closing of the Chesapeake Bay Bridge-Tunnel (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 31 (1976) Regulations Governing Certain State-Owned Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 32 (1976) Establish a Statewide Health Coordinating Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 33 (1976) Travel Regulations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 34 (1976) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Administration and Finance (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 35 (1976) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Commerce and Resources (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 36 (1976) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Education (Box 1, Folder 4)